<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Savant</name>
		<update version="0.4.1">
			<file name="class-savant.xml" url="#" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Savant" type="Class" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_SAVANT">
		<description>
			<p>The slender elf cleans his glasses with the corner of his cloak as the dust settles around him. He was the first living thing to set foot in the ancient temple in hundreds of years. His benefactor had paid him a great deal to find this place, and after months of pouring over forgotten tomes he had finally figured out it's long-lost location. Now, he had a choice to make, would he report back to his benefactor allowing them to strip the temple of it's valuables? Or, would he keep the location hidden, and preserve the priceless information found here himself? To a savant, knowledge is more precious than gold coins.</p>
			<p class="indent">The elderly warrior assessed the state of his men, they were exhausted and almost out of supplies. This was the tenth day of the siege, and the warrior knew that at this point no reinforcements were coming to relieve them. He was too old to be of use in battle, but if his men followed his orders to the letter, and without hesitation, they just might have a fighting chance. He stood up, and for what could be the last time, drew his sword.</p>
			<p class="indent">A young dwarf bends over his unconscious comrade in the midst of battle, his hands shaking as he examined the unconscious soldier's wounds. The elders of his clan had spent a great deal of their fortune to send him to the best university gold could buy. All those hours spent in lectures, libraries, and observation; all for this moment. He thought back to what he had learned about field medicine from his professors and began to dress the soldier's wounds.</p>
			<h4>GREAT MINDS</h4>
			<p>There are many intelligent people in the world, but few are true savants. Born with an innate desire to learn all they can, and the potential for a genius level intellect, they spend their lives studying anything that those around them are willing to teach them. Savants are often recognized at an early age, and in their hunger for knowledge, they are drawn to great libraries, universities, and other places of higher learning. They will do anything to access the troves of knowledge that lie hidden in the forgotten places of the world, for savants, no price is too steep to pay for a new discovery.</p>
			<p class="indent">Despite their aptitude for learning, most savants seek to better themselves without having to rely on outside influences. Savants reject the patronage of gods and other powerful beings, and in turn they view wizardry as a shortcut to power for the weak willed. Relying on their intellect alone, they strive for perfection.</p>
			<h4>INTENSE FOCUS</h4>
			<p>Savants tend to hyper-focus on their chosen area of expertise. They obsess over it, learning all they can about the subject. Once they reach the climax of learning in that specialty, and there is nothing anyone else can teach them, they do not move on. Instead they will go to great lengths, risking life and limb, to advance their chosen field of study. Often doing so at great cost to themselves, savants will not stop researching, experimenting, and theorizing until they have made an indelible mark on their academic discipline. A savant's ultimate goal in life is to discover some previously unknown truth about the universe.</p>
			<h4>CREATING A SAVANT</h4>
			<p>When creating your savant consider their upbringing and level of formal education. Were they the star pupil of the kingdom's university? Or did they come from nothing, fighting for any scrap of knowledge they could get their hands on? Were they naturally intelligent, but unable to use their abilities because of obligations to family?</p>
			<p class="indent">Whatever their origins, consider why they became an adventurer rather than an academic. Did they learn all they could from the dusty tomes in the library, and now they seek to discover forgotten temples and the knowledge within? Have they advanced beyond study and look to the endless discoveries of a life of adventure?</p>
			<h5>MULTICLASSING</h5>
			<p>If your group uses the optional rule for multiclassing in the Player's Handbook, here's what you need to know if you choose the savant as one of your classes.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Ability Score Minimum.</em> In order to multiclass, you must have at least a 13 in Intelligence to take a level in this class, or to take a level in another class if you are already a savant.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em>Proficiencies Gained.</em> If savant isn't your initial class, you gain proficiency in one set of Artisan's Tools of your choice and one skill from the savant list when you take your first level in this class.</p>
			<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make a savant quickly by following these suggestions. First, put your highest ability score in Intelligence, followed by Dexterity. Second, choose the <em>Sage</em> background from the Player's Handbook.</p>
			<h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
			<p>As a savant, you gain the following class features:</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per savant level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per savant level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light Armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, hand crossbows, rapiers, whips</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Two sets of Artisan's Tools of your choice</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Intelligence, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose three skills from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Persuasion, Religion and Slight of Hand</li>
            </ul>
			<h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
			<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Any two simple weapons of your choice</li>
				<li><i>(a)</i> a light crossbow and 20 bolts or <i>(b)</i> a rapier</li>
				<li>One set of artisan's tools of your choice</li>
				<li>Leather armor and a scholar's pack</li>
			</ul>
			<h5 class="caption">THE SAVANT</h5>
			<table class="class-features">
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="center">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="left">Features</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Adroit Analysis, Unarmored Defense</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Perfect Recall, Unyielding Mind (1d4)</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Academic Discipline</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Accelerated Reflexes (2), Potent Observation</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Expert Student</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Academic Discipline Feature</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Expert Educator</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Unyielding Mind (1d6)</td></tr>
				<tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Discerning Strike</td></tr>
				<tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Academic Discipline Feature</td></tr>
				<tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Mental Fortitude</td></tr>
				<tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Unyielding Mind (1d8)</td></tr>
				<tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Academic Discipline Feature, Accelerated Reflexes (3)</td></tr>
				<tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Profound Insight</td></tr>
				<tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
				<tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Undisputed Genius, Unyielding Mind (1d10)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_ADROIT_ANALYSIS" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_PERFECT_RECALL" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_UNYIELDING_MIND" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_ACADEMIC_DICIPLINE" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_SAVANT" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_ACCELERATED_REFLEXES" />			
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_POTENT_OBSERVATION" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_EXPERT_STUDENT" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_EXPERT_EDIUCATOR" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_DISCERNING_STRIKE" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_MENTAL_FORTITUDE" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_PROFOUND_INSIGHT" />
			<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_UNDISPUTED_GENIUS" />

		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>A Brilliant genius, using their knowledge to aid them in and out of combat.</description>
		</sheet>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">A Brilliant genius, using their knowledge to aid them in and out of combat.</set>
			<set name="hd">d8</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_MULTICLASS_SAVANT"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_MULTICLASS_SAVANT"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" requirements="!ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_MULTICLASS_SAVANT"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_MULTICLASS_SAVANT"/>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Savant)" supports="Skill,Savant" number="1" requirements="!ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_MULTICLASS_SAVANT"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_ADROIT_ANALYSIS" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_PERFECT_RECALL" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_UNYIELDING_MIND" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_ACADEMIC_DICIPLINE" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_SAVANT" level="4"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_ACCELERATED_REFLEXES" level="5"/>
			
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_POTENT_OBSERVATION" level="5"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_EXPERT_STUDENT" level="6"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_EXPERT_EDIUCATOR" level="9"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_DISCERNING_STRIKE" level="11"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_MENTAL_FORTITUDE" level="14"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_PROFOUND_INSIGHT" level="18"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_UNDISPUTED_GENIUS" level="20"/>
		</rules>

		<multiclass id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_MULTICLASS_SAVANT">
			<prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[int:13]</requirements>
			<setters>
				<set name="multiclass proficiencies">One Artisan's Tools of your choosing and one skill from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Persuasion, Religion and Slight of Hand.</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
			</rules>
		</multiclass>
	</element>

<!--
####################################
####							####
####							####
####		CLASS FEATURES		####
####							####
####							####
####################################
-->


	<element name="Adroit Analysis" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_ADROIT_ANALYSIS">
		<description>
			<p>starting at 1st level, you can make use of your lightning fast cognitive skills even as you engage in battle. As a bonus action on your turn, you can make an ability check with any skill or tool you are proficient with.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can also use this ability to analyze the movement patterns and fighting style of an enemy creature. As a bonus action, choose a creature that you can see within 60 feet. You designate it as the target of your analysis, and whenever you make a weapon attack against the designated creature you can use Intelligence, in place of Strength or Dexterity, for the weapon attack and damage rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent">The Adroit Analysis mark lasts for one minute, or until you fall unconscious. If you attempt to use this ability to mark another creature, the mark immediately ends for the first creature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description><p>As a bonus action on your turn, you can make an ability check with any skill or tool you are proficient with.</p>
			<p>As a bonus action, choose a creature that you can see within 60 feet as the target of your analysis. Whenever you make a weapon attack against the creature you can use Intelligence, in place of Strength or Dexterity, for the weapon attack and damage rolls.</p>
			<p>If you attempt to use this ability to mark another creature, the mark immediately ends for the first creature.</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Unarmored Defense" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_UNARMORED_DEFENSE">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 1st level, your observant way of fighting allows you to predict enemy attacks and react to them with lightning fast accuracy. When you are not wearing any armor or using a shield your armor class is equal to 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Intelligence modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you are not wearing any armor or using a shield your armor class is equal to 10 + {{dexterity:modifier}} + your {{intelligence:modifier}}.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
		<!--SET AC-->
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Perfect Recall" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_PERFECT_RECALL">
		<description>
			<p>Your photographic memory allows you to remember even the most minute details. Starting at 1st level, if you spend at least one minute observing and committing something to memory you can automatically recall any information about your observations at any point in the future.</p>
			<p class="indent">Examples include things you've read or studied, the appearances of people you've met, the layout of rooms, maps of dungeons or fortresses, and paths you've traveled.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>If you spend at least one minute observing and committing something to memory you can automatically recall any information about your observations at any point in the future.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Unyielding Mind" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_UNYIELDING_MIND">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 2nd level, your mind has been honed into both a potent observational weapon and a stalwart shield against mental assaults. As a reaction, when you make an Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma ability check or a saving throw, you can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the result of the ability check or saving throw. If it is for a saving throw, you use this feature after you roll, but before you determine whether you succeed or fail.</p>
			<p class="indent">The size of the die you roll for this ability increases at 10th level (1d6), 15th level (1d8), and 20th level (1d10).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As a reaction, when you make an Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma ability check or a saving throw, you can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the result of the ability check or saving throw. If it is for a saving throw, you use this feature after you roll, but before you determine whether you succeed or fail. The die increace at 10th level (1d6), 15th level (1d8), and 20th level (1d10).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Academic Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_ACADEMIC_DICIPLINE">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you choose your Academic Discipline. Choose between Archaeologist, Naturalist, Philosopher, Physician, Seeker, or Tactician, each of which is detailed at the end of this class description. Your Academic Discipline grants you features at 3rd, 7th, 13th, and 17th levels.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype" name="Academic Discipline" supports="Academic Discipline" level="3"/>
		</rules>
	</element>


	<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_SAVANT">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Savant 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Savant,4" level="4" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Savant 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Savant,8" level="8" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Savant 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Savant,12" level="12" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Savant 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Savant,16" level="16" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Savant 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Savant,19" level="19" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Accelerated Reflexes" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_ACCELERATED_REFLEXES">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 5th level, your ability to process the world around you moves notably faster. You can take one additional reaction per round. Once you use both reactions you cannot take another until the beginning of your next turn. A single effect can only trigger one reaction.</p>
			<p class="indent">Upon reaching 17th level you can take up to three reactions per round of combat.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>You can take one additional reaction per round. Once you use both reactions you cannot take another until the beginning of your next turn. A single effect can only trigger one reaction.</description>
			<description level="17">Upon reaching 17th level you can take up to three reactions per round of combat.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>

		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Potent Observation" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_POTENT_OBSERVATION">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 5th level, you use your acute observational skills to highlight the weak points of your foes for your allies. When a creature that you can see hits the target of your Adroit Analysis with a weapon or spell attack, you can use your reaction to increase the damage of the attack by 1d10. If the attack deals more then one type of damage the creature making the attack chooses the damage type of this bonus damage on hit.</p>
			<p class="indent">Upon reaching 11th level in this class, the bonus damage from this ability increases to 2d10.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>When a creature that you can see hits the target of your Adroit Analysis with a weapon or spell attack, you can use your reaction to increase the damage of the attack by 1d10. If the attack deals more then one type of damage the creature making the attack chooses the damage type of this bonus damage on hit.</description>
			<description level="11">Upon reaching 11th level in this class, the bonus damage from this ability increases to 2d10.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>

		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Expert Student" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_EXPERT_STUDENT">
		<description>
			<p>Upon reaching 6th level, your ability to learn is unrivaled. At the end of a short or long rest you can choose to learn one additional language of your choice, or gain one tool, skill, or weapon proficiency of your choice, as long as there is an example on hand for you to learn from (like a teacher, a manual, a book in a different language, or fellow party member). You can gain only one bonus proficiency from this feature per short or long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can have a number of bonus proficiencies from this ability equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1). If you learn another while at your maximum you must choose one proficiency you gained from this ability to forget.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Short/Long Rest">
			<description>At the end of a short or long rest you can choose to learn one additional language of your choice, or gain one tool, skill, or weapon proficiency of your choice, as long as there is an example on hand for you to learn from (like a teacher, a manual, a book in a different language, or fellow party member). You can gain only one bonus proficiency from this feature per short or long rest. You can have {{intelligence:modifier}} bonus proficiencies from this ability.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>

		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Expert Educator" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_EXPERT_EDIUCATOR">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 9th level you have mastered the art of sharing your knowledge with others. Choose one skill, tool, or weapon you are proficient with, or one language you know. At the end of a long rest, a number of creatures of your choice equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1) that can hear you gain that proficiency or learn the language. The benefits of this ability last until the end of your next long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">The proficiency or language you choose to teach with this ability can be one that you've acquired from Expert Student.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Short/Long Rest">
			<description>Beginning at 9th level you have mastered the art of sharing your knowledge with others. Choose one skill, tool, or weapon you are proficient with, or one language you know. At the end of a long rest, {{intelligence:modifier}} creatures that can hear you gain that proficiency or learn the language. The benefits of this ability last until the end of your next long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>

		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Discerning Strike" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_DISCERNING_STRIKE">
		<description>
			<p>At 11th level, your analytical mind allows you to land devastating counterattacks as your enemy strikes at you. When a creature that you have designated as the target of your Adroit Analysis makes a weapon or spell attack against you, you can use your reaction to immediately make one attack against that creature, regardless if the triggering attack hits you.</p>
			<p class="indent">If your special reaction attack hits you gain a bonus to the damage roll equal to your Potent Observation bonus.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>You can counterattacks an enemy that attacks you. When a creature that you have designated as the target of your Adroit Analysis makes a weapon or spell attack against you, you can use your reaction to immediately make one attack against that creature, regardless if the triggering attack hits.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>

		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Mental Fortitude" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_MENTAL_FORTITUDE">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 14th level you have learned to steel your mind against effects that remove your mental agency. If you fail a saving throw to resist being charmed, frightened, or stunned, you can choose to automatically succeed instead.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this ability you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>If you fail a saving throw to resist being charmed, frightened, or stunned, you can choose to automatically succeed instead. Once you use this ability you must complete a short or long rest before you can use it again.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>

		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Profound Insight" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_PROFOUND_INSIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 18th level, your almost supernatural ability to process the world around you allows you to predict your enemy's attacks as they happen. When an enemy creature is designated by Adroit Analysis they have disadvantage on any attack roll they make against you, and you have advantage on any saving throw they force you to make.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>When an enemy creature is designated by Adroit Analysis they have disadvantage on any attack roll they make against you, and you have advantage on any saving throw they force you to make.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>

		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Undisputed Genius" type="Class Feature" source="Numidius" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_CLASS_FEATURE_UNDISPUTED_GENIUS">
		<description>
			<p>Upon reaching 20th level, you realize the wondrous potential of your intellect. Both your Intelligence score, and maximum Intelligence score, increase by 4.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="flase"/>
		<rules>
	
		</rules>
	</element>

<!--
############################################
####									####
####									####
####									####
####		ACADEMIC DISCIPLINES		####
####									####
####									####
####									####
############################################
-->

<!--
############################################
####									####
####			ARCHAEOLOGIST			####
####									####
############################################
-->
<element name="Archaeologist" type="Archetype" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST">
	<supports>Academic Discipline</supports>
	<description>
			<p>Specializing in the study of ancient places, forgotten cities, and uncharted lands, Archaeologists boldly walk into the dark and deadly places of the world that they may be illuminated by the light of knowledge. Archaeologists do their best to piece together the lost knowledge of past ages. They tend to feel a sad kinship with the lost civilizations that they study, and will go to great lengths not to destroy or offend their memory. For an Archaeologist, learning from the innovations, and mistakes, of the past is the best way to improve the present and move towards a better future.</p>
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_STUDENT_OF_HISTORY" />
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_DARING_DETERMINATION" />
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_SURVIVALIST" />
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_LORE_MASTER" />
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_MASTER_ARCHAEOLOGIST" />
	</description>
	<sheet display="false">
		<description>Bards of the College of Lore know something about most things, collecting bits of knowledge from sources as diverse as scholarly tomes and peasant tales.</description>
	</sheet>
	<rules>
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_STUDENT_OF_HISTORY" level="3" />
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_DARING_DETERMINATION" level="3" />
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_SURVIVALIST" level="7" />
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_LORE_MASTER" level="13" />
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_MASTER_ARCHAEOLOGIST" level="17" />
	</rules>
</element>
<!--
############################################
####									####
####			NATURALIST				####
####									####
############################################
-->
<element name="Naturalist" type="Archetype" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_NATURALIST">
	<supports>Academic Discipline</supports>
	<description>
		<p>The Naturalist's classroom begins at the very edges of civilization. They study the environments that exist beyond the influence of civilized peoples. Naturalists are experts at anticipating weather patterns, knowing the difference between an edible plant and a toxic one, and understanding the behaviors of wild animals. Highly sought after as guides for adventuring parties, Naturalists can safely navigate arid deserts, frigid mountain ranges, and treacherous jungles.</p>
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_NATURALIST_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_STUDENT_OF_NATURE" />
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_CONSERVATIONIST" />
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_OUTDOORSMAN" />
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_WILD_INSIGHTS" />
		<div element="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_MASTER_NATURALIST" />
	</description>
	<sheet display="false">
		<description>Bards of the College of Lore know something about most things, collecting bits of knowledge from sources as diverse as scholarly tomes and peasant tales.</description>
	</sheet>
	<rules>
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_NATURALIST_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_STUDENT_OF_NATURE" level="3" />
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_CONSERVATIONIST" level="3" />
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_OUTDOORSMAN" level="7" />
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_WILD_INSIGHTS" level="13" />
		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZIMO_NUMIDIUS_ARCHETYPE_ARCHAEOLOGIST_MASTER_NATURALIST" level="17" />
	</rules>
</element>
<!--
############################################
####									####
####			PHILOSOPHER				####
####									####
############################################
-->

<!--
############################################
####									####
####			SEEKER					####
####									####
############################################
-->

<!--
############################################
####									####
####			TACTICIAN				####
####									####
############################################
-->


	
</elements>